hello
my name is green welcome back to another
episode of hermitcraft now the potato
has been completed without any of the
redstone and definitely without any of
the villagers it's got one two three
layers it's not oh wait no four layers
down the bottom it's not that good and
it's probably not going to produce much
but it's going to produce more potatoes
than i can eat so that's the main thing
it's just meant to be my private food
supply and hopefully i think it'll
actually look a lot better than this
this looks like a total mess but this
should look good the only problem is i
need to get my hands on some villagers
now to get those i'm gonna have to
create a railway
all the way over to mumbo's base
which is going to be an absolute
nightmare so basically his villager
breeder isn't working it's right here so
i need to create
a working system
from here
all the way over to my base something
that i can build quickly and take down
quickly just to transport four villages
if only i could use a lead on these guys
it'd be so much easier but
oh well this is what's got to be done
yep i'm afraid this is a bit of a dull
start to the video but it's got to be
done i've already asked mumbo about this
but this would be really funny actually
if he just logged on he's like what the
heck but no i've got his permission it's
going to be very very temporary to get
hold of these farming villages for my
little potato i actually want to get
this done fairly quickly because as i
speak and maybe some of you were there
watching it but mumbo jumbo is actually
live streaming his
big hole dig and i actually bought 100
stacks of tnt from cub for the war but
never got to use them
look at this and i've got like four more
of these in my ender chest so i'm
thinking maybe we pop over there and we
help him out the only way we know how oh
actually you know what that didn't
actually take too long i'm almost there
and we're done actually that only took
like 10 minutes believe it or not it was
just a very painful 10 minutes so i just
need to put some rails all the way along
this
really really hideous
long
rail cart system so that i can get my
hands on some farming villagers that's
honestly the best way that i could think
of doing it i probably could have put
them in a boat and voted them over but
this way i just save a bunch of trips
basically i think since i only took 10
minutes really not a big deal anyway
let's go and see if mumbo could use my
help
ah i think i found it so i think the
plan for this is a giant witch farm boy
it's a little bit laggy here no wonder
it's laggy look at all these items
gee i wonder why it's laggy here mumbo
[Laughter]
no wonder he's complaining about the lag
look at all this junk
now i wonder i could do a little
experiment here mumbo has no idea so i
could just see
he's streaming over there he's literally
just streaming hours and hours and hours
of digging so maybe just on the sly
i can
make a little bit of a explosion
he's only over there so he's
look at this stop complaining about the
lag and then making the lag you know
what
if he's gonna complain about the lag i'm
gonna make him really complain about the
lag
i want that back
oh
that's that's the that's the quickest
way to do it
it's not the cleanest way but it works
hopefully we have a winner
there we go
[Music]
that's how we do it
it's not about if i'm going to fall into
lava at this point it's about when i'm
going to fall into lava
[Music]
and i live to tell another tnt tale
i have no idea if this is going to work
i just i've asked him if he wants to
watch
well there we go
[Music]
oh
boy
oh no
it was too powerful
i think maybe tnt just isn't the way to
go unfortunately
it's just it's just way too
unpredictable it might even be quicker
just to
mine this out the old-fashioned way well
i guess i'll just help mumbo for a bit
and then hopefully i can meet up with
mumbo a little later on to discuss
our architect projects and our future
ideas for what we're going to do
architect is officially
making a comeback on the hermitcraft
server we haven't done enough with it
and now we're bringing it back so about
five hours later and a big live stream
there's basically just a
complete mess
i used quite a bit of my tnt all of this
used to be tnt here
and
you can see you can see where mumbo's
been digging because it's all here it's
all the neat bit the traditional way you
can see where i've been
been helping this is five hours by the
way and it's not even finished a quarter
of it i'd say there's about half
of one quarter so
12.5 of the whole thing
absolutely ridiculous
so i think this is going to take
something a bit more than a few pickaxes
and
let's say 60 hours of mining
so i think mumbo's gonna have to come up
with a different idea because i am
definitely not minding this anymore but
i thought it'd be nice to help
nonetheless because projects like this
do take an awful long time but i think
we're gonna have to head back to the
base because
yeah there's no way i'm going to do any
more of this
so hopefully later on once i've got this
done not only can i meet up with mumbo
to talk about the architect project that
we're going to be doing but also
hopefully he can sort out that villager
breeder and send over my new farmers
because yeah this is gonna take a long
time to do
now if we're going to be meeting up with
mumbo we really need to fix yeah we need
to fix the infinity meeting room because
i borrowed
and i do mean borrowed every single item
frame and map in here because they're
very expensive to make so i'm gonna have
to transfer all of them over from the g
team base
back over here which is going to be an
absolute pain
it feels weird being back in here to be
honest with you ah
oh please tell me i didn't lose my stuff
i completely forgot that the place is
still booby trapped oh
let's see what the damage is oh no
please
tell me my stuff
pickaxe is okay
i think i lost my armor i can't i can't
believe it that's so annoying i've lost
so much maybe it's down here
oh no oh and i totally forgot about
gimme
gimme gimme never got used during the
war unfortunately i think he's still
here yeah there he is perhaps we'll um
we'll we'll put him up for adoption or
something
oh i really can't believe i've lost my
stuff this is
this is the most devastating thing oh
yeah but of course the sticks survived
don't worry about that the sticks have
survived please tell me there's they're
just somewhere
somewhere
do you have any idea oh no
please
i've got a box full of kind of
replacement stuff but it's it's never
going to be the same
oh this is not good
not good at all i totally forgot about
mumbo's stupid traps we should have
disabled these a long time ago
i think i'm gonna have to accept that my
stuff is gone properly gone
out of everything that survived
this is what i got left
junk my elytra
all of my armor
gone
well there's no point getting upset
about it let's move on we still need to
go and get that infinity room set up
because mumbo's just come online to do
the meeting i assume
and now i'm gonna have to tell him
and now i'm gonna have to inform him
what's gone on actually while we're here
it'd be a really good opportunity to
loot a lot of the stuff left in the g
team base i think it's every man for
himself pretty much
i don't think mumbo's fake door traps
got anybody except me and stress well
stresses rabbit
right well
you know what i think i'm just i'm just
going to try and do this myself
got to get in there anyway
what
oh no no no no i forgot about the
how did lytra on
ah
today
today is just not my day
where did this guy come from
when where did this guy come from
what is going on this episode
you
who are you
stay you're meant to be up there
oh my goodness okay let's get this oh
i'm i'm having a terrible day i'm gonna
have to re-enchant all of my stuff
it's not gonna be fun
i think we've all had these days in
minecraft but today is
a particularly bad day i must admit i
don't think i've died this many times in
a row
oh man okay give me an hour and i'm
gonna get everything back the way it was
and we're gonna continue like absolutely
nothing happened okay let's see here
i've got my trident fax machine axe
machine silk machine
mostly back
uh we're back
and absolutely nothing went wrong you
know what i think just to be on the safe
side let's get rid of those shall we
let's just get rid of any chance that
they're gonna blow up again i mean blow
up at all
oh goodness that took about an hour to
get myself back where i was you know
what this time i think i'm just gonna
skip my own parkour oh look i did it
you know i'm not even gonna risk this
either let's let's pop on through go all
the way through the maze
yeah you've made it now i need to get
back all of these
now i've quite had enough of dying
especially into lava
so i'm gonna make sure
that there are no accidents that happen
in this room
maps and item frames are very very
expensive now there's another one here
not gonna let this one get me either
okay we're safe
oh this meeting's been a nightmare
let's recover all of these lanterns this
was a very expensive room to make okay
i'm not gonna go and collect all this
stuff again now i know it's a bit of a
monument to this but
truth is i really need these resources i
think i'd prefer to have my meeting room
back then leave this trap that didn't
even get fall for false was too clever
for it
and we're done
thank goodness for that and i have a
feeling that this won't even cover
everything that i need okay and now we
can exit and i think since i've lost all
of those items yet again that i had on
me i should try and loot what i can from
the g team base and just get the heck
out of here and never come back
uh this this this war we may have won
but i feel like i've just lost now to be
fair most of these dispensers are
actually mine so i think i'll just take
these back to be fair
there's not an awful lot of stuff that's
of value and i think it's already been
looted to be honest with you people have
already taken the useful stuff i think
this is our final goodbye to the g team
base
we won't be coming back here and i think
as a little symbol of goodbye i'm gonna
break the bed it's been fun g team bass
except for the last two hours i hope
that everyone enjoyed this war but i
think this is the absolute last time
that we will be back here goodbye g team
bass it's been fun
i don't think you guys know how big of a
deal it is to lose all of your stuff in
hermitcraft like all of these tools are
very expensive and all of these
enchantments take such a long time to
get back so
i'm glad that it's back but what a waste
of time that was i barely got anything
out of it right let's go and repair this
room so we can have our meeting with
mumbo
and last one
and it is officially complete i've
changed it up with some quartz chairs
instead of the spruce ones and i've got
like a little architect logo here and i
had to change it up so that there was
nothing attached to the sea lanterns but
i think that looks pretty good this is
this is a good start to do our meeting
this will be the second official
architect meeting all right now it's
time to see if mumbo is ready mumbo
finally hello um you know the war's over
right yeah it's funny that you say that
i've it's it's been one of those things
that's been on my to-do list to get my
must we actually look surprisingly
similar-ish with
without me having a mustache
no i don't know i disagree i
disagree i've kind of gotten used to
having the the no mustache i'm gonna be
honest and that's not okay that's why we
need to go and get that mustache back on
that face because it's been yeah it's
been off far too long you know what i
don't know i don't know if it's even
worth using the machine for money
anymore because it's it's not a pleasant
experience for anybody
no no no we might have to put up the
prices because yeah this is horrible
i've i've received non-stop blood every
single time i log on to the server
either iskall or ren or someone will say
something awful about my face so it is
getting a little bit disheartening i
have to say all right let's go let's go
get it let's go get it quickly before
the
the whole thing gets blocked off all
right i'm gonna try and take off in your
base okay cool i'm on my way oh yeah i'm
on my way yeah i'm off
i'm i'm off i'm away
i'm crashing to your wall i'm off
[Music]
i just took full damage in the sky just
then why is my connection
right now how you have so much issue
with flying and you're going the wrong
way
oh oh look at you doing some red arrows
stuff
[Laughter]
something awful happened
right can you oh i can see there's i
totally forgot that you trapped all this
stuff i just i came blundering in like
oh it's so good to be
gone
dude i lost all my stuff i've had to go
and spend an hour re-gearing myself it's
not been pleasant
oh wait i'm really sorry about that why
are we even here your mustache isn't
even here dude we're here for your
message
on the bright side i mean you are the
only person that got killed by one of
one of the traps so
i think this kind of this that
summarizes my involvement in the war
you're gonna make me cry
let's get this back on your face and
never come back here ever again what's
that thing like you should it should be
that you you only see it's ten thousand
hours isn't it if you spend ten thousand
hours on something you should be like an
expert at it
and i feel like that doesn't apply i've
definitely spent ten thousand hours on
minecraft and i i'm 100
not an expert
what does that say about us
i i don't know and i don't want to think
about it too much to be honest with you
yeah let's go and put this mustache back
on your face
yeah yeah let's just let's just let's
just walk away from that problem just
ignore it entirely all right i've got
the i've got a dispenser here for you
let's pop this okay
do you have a lever or anything like
that
would you like um would you like a shane
booth
a shame booth yeah shane booth
while i'm changing
you're gonna have to activate the lever
of course
oh yeah i got this for you you ready
okay yep three two
oh wait i haven't actually put the
mustache back
there we go right ready
what would have happened i put my half
in yeah you would have had half a
mustache
and
go
yeah
it always itches when this is happening
it tickles
how how big is my mustache again
it scales it scales
okay
[Music]
is it done i think that's it
i think that's it empty
how do i look
like you've got
wait what
mumbo what's going on
what has happened to me have you gone
too long you've got that you've got
double master you've got double
mustache i was i was like wait a minute
something doesn't look right here
how have you done this
where you play hang on
we must have put the wrong number of
blocks into the system
you're like you're like 50 percent more
man now
i'm making up for it all the time spend
money
i've come back with twice as much
oh it's like something doesn't look
right here well you gotta leave it like
that now
this is this is my life this is my life
now this is this is how i'm gonna be
anyway
what i've called you here for is
actually the the architect meeting the
second one we've only we didn't really
do much with architects yet so i think
it's time that we did down the hill yeah
yeah
i hate this place what i hate what
you've done with the place what do you
mean i got two lovely chairs
i know
you always do there's always there's
always fun it's just set up in this
strange
kind of yeah void it's
it's uncomfortable it's it's it's it's
very us you know
yeah well it's so that we can focus
really focusing on what each other are
saying focus on that double mustache
thing going on you've got
going over there it's
it's freaking me out dude
it's horrendous
we're gonna have to we're gonna have to
shave one of those off okay so i've got
like our little architect logo here yep
and basically my base is pretty much
finished i don't know about yours yeah
it's getting there i mean there's still
like a few projects left to do but for
the most part it's it's almost done so
i'm ready to get fully committed into a
couple of architect projects and the
only one that i really have in mind at
the moment is the railway station that
i've been putting off for about
five months now
[Laughter]
well that definitely sounds good i've
actually been
uh in some of my episodes lately i've
been kind of throwing out this idea that
i'd really like to make
amazon in minecraft because i'd love it
if there was some way that we could have
a shop that sells everything and amazon
i mean i've always been kind of throwing
it out there as like wouldn't that be
cool
it's only just occurred to me now that
there's no distractions or anything like
that and i'm staring deeply into your
eyes that
we could totally do something like this
together so we make a like a giant
warehouse and do we deliver is that is
that the idea do we deliver to people i
mean i i don't know about delivery
deliveries would be complicated but i
think some form of just gigantic store
like a warehouse type thing maybe with
some like advanced redstone maybe with
kind of like a semi delivery system type
thing okay uh i'm listening it could be
done and i think it could be
i think it could be cool and i i really
what does it sell it sells everything or
most things
most things and yeah you do know that
concorp also sell most things on the
server
yes but we're more handsome you
you're right there
you go you got me there
but no i mean yeah they would be
definitely i guess competition in a way
kind of hadn't thought that far ahead
but i just think it would be fun to just
construct something like that no i like
you know i'm
this sounds like a massive massive
project though yeah it's a big one i've
i'm just starting to realize just like
my witch hut that i've started doing
that's going to take 1.2 million blocks
to clear just as like just as it's come
out of my mouth just now i've just
realized we might need help yeah i'm
thinking the same thing
well
did you see iskall's latest video or the
one just i actually
i actually i actually haven't do you
want to explain at the end of the video
he showed
that he was the person that changed the
sign that led me to the prank on the
ghost ship so basically single-handedly
iskall escalated the entire war into the
whole g-team vs star
and that's pretty crazy it's pretty
funny i mean that's that was
it's genius that is hilarious yeah it's
really funny so i mean
that's the sort of qualities i admire in
someone you know
marketing he's definitely he's he's got
like he's got a lot of people involved
off of very simple action we could do
with that so um should we invite him to
architects because i mean we could
really use the manpower on something
like this yeah we can always i mean he's
just recently pressed he's placed 50 000
buttons recently so i'm sure he's open
to more grundy projects i'm sure he's
going to burn out if anything he can
collect the courts
[Laughter]
okay that sounds good though
hmm
why don't you leave the the invitation
to me i'm gonna
i'm gonna deliver it in his base in
i do you know what we're gonna do should
we go and get a letter let's go and
write him a letter and then i'm gonna
build something oh the exit's right here
by the way okay yeah yeah you you can't
just wander out of the room like that
there's no invisible landmarks or
anything
so i'm thinking we write him a letter
and i'm gonna build something epic in
his base to deliver it
when i've got time what do you think
right
that sounds good to me i mean
yeah i'm i'm curious to see what this
epic thing is going to be that's going
to deliver it oh it's because i i i
don't know yet but i'm going to think of
something don't you worry but we'll just
get the letter sorted for now i mean
what what's it going to say how long is
it going to take to write
iska how fast are you at writing
uh
kid tech
lol question mark
what do you think of this
what do you what do you take take a look
at that i don't even know if i spelt
architect right i was
i'm not sure
but yeah that looks good to me that's a
true labor of love that is up there this
will be studied years from now alongside
shakespeare
he's i don't think this is even a formal
invitation this is iskall architect lol
it's definitely good enough
yeah
i'll deliver this to him at some point
all right sounds good to me man i'm
looking forward to this one all right
i'm gonna work on building the train
station then while you start planning
out some of the stuff for the amazon
project but we need we need a name we
can't we can't call it amazon it's yeah
it's not good
you have to call it something else uh
maybe maybe
a maze on
just amazing i mean we can be amazing
now because architect's amazing let's
let's see i think we should hear some of
the suggestions in the comments and then
hopefully we can work out something i
mean we haven't started yet so we've got
time to come up with a name
of course no well i mean you know they
came did they come up with architects i
can't remember what was your favorite
yeah they did actually yeah it was
originally built stone but architects is
so much cooler
[Laughter]
all right sorry for blasting our name
i'll get back to my stuff now all right
i can't
wait i said i said don't don't worry
i'll get back to my stuff now
yeah i'll i'll get back to my stuff now
i'll be off
when is he gonna realize
look it's been nice seeing you mate i'll
i'll see you soon it's been really good
what is going on
[Laughter]
oh as i was saying it's been nice to see
you
oh it's no better
you know what just see you bye
after that i'm afraid that is all we
have time for in today's episode yep i'm
in the uh zombie farm right now because
i'm trying to get a bunch of tridents
i've been here a while now and i've only
got one trident basically because of
this whole uh warehouse project that
we're going to be doing i think a really
good thing to sell would be did you die
boxes just because of what's happened in
today's episode i died three times and i
lost all my armor and it was an absolute
nightmare so what i'm thinking is i sell
a full shulker box full of
tools so you would get a trident two
pickaxes sword shovel axe and then all
of these things as well and i think that
would sell really well and i'm gonna
charge over the odds for it so i need to
collect a bunch of tridents but to be
honest with you these boxes are what i
would use if i died but i thought maybe
i could make you know ten of them maybe
and sell them at three stacks of
diamonds because you know if you die in
an episode you don't want to spend an
hour getting your stuff back so there's
such a demand there that there is a good
opportunity for some business in there
well
you can see how much i've been farming
here but regardless thank you very much
for watching everyone i hope you've
enjoyed this episode in particular it
was very very funny and also very
painful and i look forward to seeing
your suggestions in the comments let me
know what you think and all of that kind
of stuff thank you very much for
watching everyone and good bye